<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-10-14T18:27:48+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Roman Surkoff</title><subtitle>An experienced software engineer</subtitle><entry><title type="html">GitHub Profile Trophy: enhance your profile</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/GitHub-Profile-Trophy" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="GitHub Profile Trophy: enhance your profile" /><published>2024-10-12T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2024-10-12T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/GitHub-Profile-Trophy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/GitHub-Profile-Trophy"><![CDATA[<p>GitHub Profile Trophy is a service that enhances your GitHub profile with visual trophies showcasing your achievements, 
such as the number of repositories and open-source contributions. To use it, visit the GitHub Profile Trophy website, 
enter your account name, and get the code to insert into your README. You can customize the trophies’ theme, 
number of columns, and categories to make your profile more engaging and visually appealing.</p>

<hr />

<p><b>GitHub Profile Trophy: enhance your profile</b></p>

<p>GitHub Profile Trophy is a service to enhance your GitHub profile with visual trophies that showcase your achievements: number of repositories, open-source contributions, and much more.</p>

<p><b>How to use?</b></p>

<p>Go to <a href="https://github-profile-trophy.vercel.app/">GitHub Profile Trophy</a>, enter your account name, and get the code to insert into your README:</p>

<p><code>[![trophy](https://github-profile-trophy.vercel.app/?username=your_username)](https://github.com/ryo-ma/github-profile-trophy)</code></p>

<p><b>Settings</b></p>

<p>You can customize the theme, number of columns, and categories:</p>

<p><code>[![trophy](https://github-profile-trophy.vercel.app/?username=your_username&amp;theme=onedark&amp;row=2&amp;column=3)]</code></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/posts/2024/00002-2.png" alt="Github profile trophy" /></p>

<p><b>Advantages</b></p>

<p><i>Visual appeal</i>: makes your profile more engaging. <i>Flexibility</i>: customize the trophies to your preferences. GitHub is your portfolio, and this service helps make it stand out and look better.</p>

<p><a href="https://github-profile-trophy.vercel.app/">Try it now</a>.</p>

<p>You can check out my trophies on <a href="https://github.com/s-rb">my profile</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="icons" /><category term="post" /><category term="github" /><category term="profile" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[GitHub Profile Trophy enhances your GitHub profile with customizable visual trophies that showcase your achievements, making your portfolio more engaging]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Deploying Multiple Apps on a Single VPS</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/deploying-multiple-apps-docker" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Deploying Multiple Apps on a Single VPS" /><published>2024-10-12T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2024-10-12T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/deploying-multiple-apps-docker</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/deploying-multiple-apps-docker"><![CDATA[<p>Deploying multiple applications on a single VPS using Docker allows for efficient isolation and management of each app 
in containers. By installing Docker and creating a docker-compose.yml file, you can easily launch and manage services 
like Node.js and PHP. Additionally, tools like Portainer provide a user-friendly web interface for streamlined 
container management, making updates and oversight simpler.</p>

<hr />

<p><b>Deploying Multiple Apps on a Single VPS with Docker</b></p>

<p>Docker enables efficient deployment of multiple applications on a single VPS by isolating them in containers. This simplifies management and updates.</p>

<p><b>Step 1: Install Docker</b></p>

<p>Install Docker on your server. For Ubuntu, use the following commands:</p>

<pre><code>sudo apt update
sudo apt install docker.io</code></pre>

<p>Start Docker:</p>

<pre><code>sudo systemctl start docker
sudo systemctl enable docker</code></pre>

<p><b>Step 2: Using Docker Compose</b></p>

<p>Create a <code>docker-compose.yml</code> file to manage your containers. Here’s an example with two apps (Node.js and PHP):</p>

<pre><code>version: '3'
services:
  node-app:
    image: node:14
    ports:
      - "3000:3000"
  php-app:
    image: php:7.4-apache
    ports:
      - "8080:80"</code></pre>

<p>Launch the services:</p>

<pre><code>docker-compose up -d</code></pre>

<p><b>Step 3: Manage via Portainer</b></p>

<p>To simplify container management, use <a href="https://www.portainer.io/">Portainer</a>, a web-based UI for managing Docker containers. To install it:</p>

<pre><code>docker run -d -p 9000:9000 --name=portainer \
--restart=always \
-v /var/run/docker.sock:/var/run/docker.sock \
-v portainer_data:/data portainer/portainer-ce</code></pre>

<p>Once installed, Portainer will be available on port <code>9000</code>.</p>

<p><b>Conclusion</b></p>

<p>Using Docker and tools like Portainer allows you to deploy and manage multiple applications on a single VPS easily, simplifying service management and updates.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="docker" /><category term="post" /><category term="vps" /><category term="portainer" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Docker enables the efficient deployment and management of multiple applications on a single VPS through containerization, simplifying updates and service management with tools like Portainer.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Commit Message Style in Git</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/commit-messages" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Commit Message Style in Git" /><published>2024-10-11T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2024-10-11T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/commit-messages</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/commit-messages"><![CDATA[<p>Maintaining a clear and structured change history in Git is essential for effective version control, and following best 
practices for commit messages can greatly enhance this process. Key guidelines include writing concise messages in the 
imperative mood, explaining the reasons for changes, and separating messages into a clear header and body. By grouping 
related changes and regularly reviewing the commit history, you can ensure better organization and collaboration 
within your projects.</p>

<hr />

<p><b>Commit Message Style in Git</b></p>

<p>Working with Git is not only about version control, but also about maintaining a change history that can be clear and structured. Below are best practices for writing commit messages:</p>

<p><b>1. Write a clear and concise message</b>
The commit message should be clear and explain the essence of the change. For example:</p>
<pre><code>git commit -m "Fixed button display on the homepage"</code></pre>

<p><b>2. Use the imperative mood</b>
Phrase commit messages in the imperative mood. This helps create consistency in the history. Example:</p>
<pre><code>git commit -m "Add date filtering capability"</code></pre>

<p><b>3. Indicate the reason for changes</b>
A good practice is to briefly explain why you made the change. For example:</p>
<pre><code>git commit -m "Optimize image loading for better performance"</code></pre>

<p><b>4. Separate messages into a header and body</b>
Use a header of up to 50 characters, and then add a more detailed description after a blank line. Example:</p>
<pre><code>
git commit -m "Update library dependencies"

Updated libraries to the latest versions for improved security and performance.
</code></pre>

<p><b>5. Group related changes</b>
Avoid creating too many small commits. Try to combine logically related changes into one commit:</p>
<pre><code>git commit -m "Add new functionality: upload and delete files"</code></pre>

<p><b>6. Avoid using timestamps</b>
Do not include time or date in messages, as this is already recorded in the commit itself. Instead, it is better to specify what was changed:</p>
<pre><code>git commit -m "Fix bug in message sending function"</code></pre>

<p><b>7. Check the commit history</b>
Regularly review the commit history using the command:</p>
<pre><code>git log --oneline</code></pre>
<p>This will help you maintain order and structure in your project.</p>

<p><b>Conclusion</b>
By following these simple rules, you will be able to create a clear and accessible change history in your project, making work easier for both you and your colleagues. <tg-emoji emoji-id="5368324170671202286">👍</tg-emoji></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="git" /><category term="post" /><category term="commit" /><category term="codestyle" /><category term="best-practice" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Following best practices for commit messages in Git, such as writing concise and imperative statements while explaining changes, helps maintain a clear and structured change history for better collaboration and project management]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">25 Powerful and Free APIs Every Developer Should Know in 2024</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/25-powerful-free-api" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="25 Powerful and Free APIs Every Developer Should Know in 2024" /><published>2024-10-10T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2024-10-10T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/25-powerful-free-api</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/25-powerful-free-api"><![CDATA[<p>Developers in 2024 have access to a variety of free APIs that can significantly enhance their projects. 
These 25 APIs range from weather data and news aggregation to AI-powered text generation and real-time exchange rates, 
allowing for diverse functionality across different application types. Whether you’re building entertainment apps with 
The Movie Database API or integrating powerful geolocation with Google Maps, these tools are invaluable for modern 
software development.</p>

<hr />

<p><b>25 Powerful and Free APIs Every Developer Should Know in 2024</b></p>

<p>In the world of development, access to powerful APIs can significantly simplify the task of creating applications. Here’s a list of 25 essential free APIs that will be useful for developers in 2024:</p>

<p><b>1. <a href="https://openweathermap.org/api">OpenWeatherMap</a></b>
Provides current weather data and forecasts. Ideal for applications related to weather.
<br /><strong>Usage:</strong> 60 calls per minute for free.</p>

<p><b>2. <a href="https://newsapi.org/">News API</a></b>
Collects the latest news from various sources to create your own news applications.
<br /><strong>Usage:</strong> 500 requests per day for free.</p>

<p><b>3. <a href="https://developers.google.com/maps/documentation">Google Maps API</a></b>
Integrates maps and geolocation features into your applications.
<br /><strong>Usage:</strong> Free tier includes $200 worth of credits monthly.</p>

<p><b>4. <a href="https://www.themoviedb.org/documentation/api">The Movie Database (TMDB) API</a></b>
Accesses information about movies, TV shows, and actors. Great for entertainment-related applications.
<br /><strong>Usage:</strong> No rate limits.</p>

<p><b>5. <a href="https://jsonplaceholder.typicode.com/">JSONPlaceholder</a></b>
Provides fake data for testing and prototyping your applications.
<br /><strong>Usage:</strong> Unlimited requests.</p>

<p><b>6. <a href="https://developer.spotify.com/documentation/web-api/">Spotify API</a></b>
Gives access to music data, playlists, and Spotify user information.
<br /><strong>Usage:</strong> Rate limits are based on user authentication; generally, around 10 requests per second.</p>

<p><b>7. <a href="https://api.github.com/">GitHub API</a></b>
Interact with GitHub: access repositories, commits, and user data.
<br /><strong>Usage:</strong> 5000 requests per hour for authenticated users.</p>

<p><b>8. <a href="https://developers.facebook.com/docs/graph-api">Facebook Graph API</a></b>
Integrates with Facebook to access user and page data.
<br /><strong>Usage:</strong> Rate limits depend on the access token type.</p>

<p><b>9. <a href="https://twitter.com/en/docs/twitter-api">Twitter API</a></b>
Access tweets and user data from Twitter.
<br /><strong>Usage:</strong> 900 requests per 15 minutes for user timeline.</p>

<p><b>10. <a href="https://www.boredapi.com/">Bored API</a></b>
Provides ideas for leisure activities if you’re unsure what to do.
<br /><strong>Usage:</strong> Unlimited requests.</p>

<p><b>11. <a href="https://api.exchangerate-api.com/">ExchangeRate API</a></b>
Offers real-time exchange rates for financial applications.
<br /><strong>Usage:</strong> 250 requests per month for free.</p>

<p><b>12. <a href="https://api.openai.com/">OpenAI API</a></b>
Leverage the power of AI for text generation and analysis.
<br /><strong>Usage:</strong> Pricing based on usage; free tier available.</p>

<p><b>13. <a href="https://ipgeolocation.io/">IP Geolocation API</a></b>
Determine user location based on their IP address.
<br /><strong>Usage:</strong> 1,000 requests per month for free.</p>

<p><b>14. <a href="https://www.feralhosting.com/api">Feral Hosting API</a></b>
Manage hosting and services through an API.
<br /><strong>Usage:</strong> Depends on the hosting plan.</p>

<p><b>15. <a href="https://developers.pocketbase.io/">PocketBase API</a></b>
A real-time database for mobile and web applications.
<br /><strong>Usage:</strong> Unlimited requests.</p>

<p><b>16. <a href="https://api.nasa.gov/">NASA API</a></b>
Access data about space, images, and NASA missions.
<br /><strong>Usage:</strong> 1,000 requests per hour for free.</p>

<p><b>17. <a href="https://docs.github.com/en/rest">GitHub REST API</a></b>
Additional access to GitHub resources and data.
<br /><strong>Usage:</strong> 5000 requests per hour for authenticated users.</p>

<p><b>18. <a href="https://developer.woocommerce.com/">WooCommerce API</a></b>
Integrates with the WooCommerce platform for online store management.
<br /><strong>Usage:</strong> Rate limits depend on server settings.</p>

<p><b>19. <a href="https://www.virustotal.com/gui/home/upload">VirusTotal API</a></b>
Checks files and URLs for viruses and threats.
<br /><strong>Usage:</strong> 4 requests per minute for free.</p>

<p><b>20. <a href="https://dog.ceo/dog-api/">Dog API</a></b>
Provides information and images of dogs for animal lovers.
<br /><strong>Usage:</strong> Unlimited requests.</p>

<p><b>21. <a href="https://catfact.ninja/">Cat Facts API</a></b>
Offers interesting facts about cats to entertain users.
<br /><strong>Usage:</strong> Unlimited requests.</p>

<p><b>22. <a href="https://rapidapi.com/">RapidAPI</a></b>
A platform for finding and integrating various APIs.
<br /><strong>Usage:</strong> Varies by individual API.</p>

<p><b>23. <a href="https://openai.com/api/">OpenAI GPT-3 API</a></b>
Creates powerful text generators and chatbots.
<br /><strong>Usage:</strong> Pricing based on usage; free tier available.</p>

<p><b>24. <a href="https://developer.yahoo.com/weather/">Yahoo Weather API</a></b>
Provides weather data from Yahoo.
<br /><strong>Usage:</strong> 2,000 requests per day for free.</p>

<p><b>25. <a href="https://www.openstreetmap.org/">OpenStreetMap API</a></b>
Access community-generated mapping data.
<br /><strong>Usage:</strong> Unlimited requests.</p>

<p><b>Conclusion</b>
These 25 APIs offer a wide range of capabilities for developers, enabling the creation of innovative applications that integrate diverse data and functionality. Use them to enhance your projects and make them more interactive. <tg-emoji emoji-id="5368324170671202286">👍</tg-emoji></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="api" /><category term="post" /><category term="developer" /><category term="free" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here is a collection of 25 powerful free APIs that developers can leverage in 2024 to simplify app development, offering everything from weather data and news to AI capabilities and geolocation.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Cool icons for github profile</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/cool-icons-for-github-profile" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cool icons for github profile" /><published>2024-10-08T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2024-10-08T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/cool-icons-for-github-profile</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/cool-icons-for-github-profile"><![CDATA[<p>Icons8 is a platform that offers a vast collection of icons for personal and commercial projects, 
available in various styles and formats. All icons can be used for free, making them an ideal resource 
for designers and developers looking to enhance the visual appeal of social media profiles, presentations, 
and websites.</p>

<hr />

<p><b>Icons for your profile and projects: Icons8</b></p>

<p>In modern design and visual content, <i>icons</i> play an important role. They help convey information quickly and effectively while adding aesthetic value. One of the best resources for finding quality icons is the website <b>Icons8</b>.</p>

<p>Icons8 is a platform offering a vast collection of icons that can be used for both personal and commercial projects. All icons are available in various styles and formats, making it easy to find the right fit for your design.</p>

<p>One of the main advantages of Icons8 is the ability to <strong>use icons for free</strong>. You don’t need to worry about licenses or copyrights—just pick your favorite icon and download it. All icons are available in various formats, including PNG, SVG, PDF, and others.</p>

<p><b>How to use these icons</b></p>

<p><b>- Profile customization</b>: Create a unique visual style for your social media or blogs. Adding icons will make your profile more attractive and memorable.</p>

<p><b>- Creating presentations</b>: Icons can help make your presentations more visually engaging and understandable. You can use them to highlight points, illustrate ideas, or simply enhance the overall slide design.</p>

<p><b>- Website development</b>: If you’re creating a website or web application, icons can be a great addition to the interface. They help users navigate the site more easily and improve the overall user experience.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/posts/2024/00001-1.png" alt="Github profile icons" /></p>

<p>To start using icons from Icons8, simply visit <a href="https://icons8.com">icons8.com</a> and use the search feature to find the icons you need. You can filter the results by style, color, and other parameters to find exactly what you’re looking for.</p>

<p>Icons8 is a great tool for any designer, developer, or even casual user who wants to improve the visual appeal of their projects. Don’t miss the chance to make your profiles and work more attractive with free icons!</p>

<p><b>Download and start using icons today!</b></p>

<p>You can check out these icons in my GitHub profile - <a href="https://github.com/s-rb">github.com/s-rb</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="icons" /><category term="post" /><category term="github" /><category term="profile" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Icons8 is a free resource offering a vast collection of icons in various styles and formats, perfect for enhancing the visual appeal of projects, presentations, and social media profiles]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Sample Post</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/sample-post" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sample Post" /><published>2020-04-24T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-04-24T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/sample-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/sample-post"><![CDATA[<p>This post will show you how the content will look like in the post pages and how the headlines, quotes and quotes will be represented. Jekyll is mainly used to write simple markdown and after that it renders out a static pages, so you need to know the basics of writing markdown for that.
For more information about writing markdown you can checkout the following markdown cheatsheets:</p>
<ul>
  <li><a href="https://guides.github.com/features/mastering-markdown/">Mastering Markdown</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.markdownguide.org/cheat-sheet/">Markdown Guide</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://github.github.com/gfm/">GitHub Flavored Markdown Spec</a></li>
</ul>

<hr />

<h1 id="this-is-the-h1-text">This is the h1 text</h1>
<h2 id="this-is-the-h2-text">This is the h2 text</h2>
<h3 id="this-is-the-h3-text">This is the h3 text</h3>
<h4 id="this-is-the-h4-text">This is the h4 text</h4>
<h5 id="this-is-the-h5-text">This is the h5 text</h5>
<h6 id="this-is-the-h6-text">This is the h6 text</h6>

<p><strong>Bold Text in the post will look like:</strong><br />
<strong>This text is Bold</strong></p>

<p><strong>Italic Text in the post will look like:</strong><br />
<em>This text is Italic</em></p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Quotes on your post will look like this</p>
</blockquote>

<p><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Codes on your post will look like this</code></p>

<p><strong>Link in the post will look like:</strong><br />
<a href="#">This is a link</a></p>

<p><strong>Bullet list in the post will look like:</strong></p>
<ul>
  <li>Item 1</li>
  <li>Item 2</li>
  <li>Item 3</li>
  <li>Item 4</li>
  <li>Item 5</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Number list in the post will look like:</strong></p>
<ol>
  <li>Item 1</li>
  <li>Item 2</li>
  <li>Item 3</li>
  <li>Item 4</li>
  <li>Item 5</li>
</ol>

<p><strong>Images in the post will look like:</strong><br />
<img src="/WhatATheme/assets/images/1280x720%20Placeholder.png" alt="Test Image" /></p>

<p><strong>Normal text in the post will look like</strong><br />
Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit. Mauris id finibus nisl. Etiam in hendrerit est. Nulla non erat ac lectus interdum lobortis. Vestibulum at mi ex. Mauris nisl mi, venenatis et feugiat nec, finibus porttitor velit. Suspendisse tincidunt lobortis leo, quis tristique tellus iaculis quis. Donec eleifend pulvinar gravida. Proin non lorem eros. Donec sit amet finibus ex, eget vestibulum nunc. Ut ut enim id purus porttitor tristique. Vivamus tincidunt eleifend hendrerit. Proin metus felis, ultrices vel dui in, porta dapibus dui. Sed sagittis ex vitae dui tristique dignissim. Cras vel leo ipsum.</p>

<p>Aenean ac neque et risus mattis accumsan. Sed ac tellus molestie, lacinia ante sit amet, convallis felis. Maecenas aliquet lectus nec euismod auctor. Donec finibus pellentesque tortor, ac efficitur metus suscipit non. Proin diam orci, blandit quis malesuada ac, efficitur a nisl. Mauris eleifend consequat blandit. Sed egestas quam et orci gravida, non euismod metus scelerisque. Curabitur venenatis pellentesque erat commodo pharetra. Fusce id ante nec ipsum fringilla auctor. In justo quam, feugiat placerat eleifend dapibus, luctus et quam. Fusce facilisis erat ut odio convallis viverra et id mauris. Sed vehicula tempus consectetur. Aliquam pharetra, purus non egestas tristique, tellus massa fringilla est, id sagittis tellus urna non mauris. Suspendisse fringilla, velit nec blandit facilisis, ligula ante imperdiet est, et placerat magna sem quis tortor.</p>

<p>Vestibulum vitae fermentum velit, rhoncus egestas orci. Nulla at purus ut orci posuere vulputate. In eget leo diam. In congue in diam nec elementum. Suspendisse fringilla ante nulla, eu tristique orci ultrices eget. Aenean non lorem tellus. Vestibulum tempor metus sit amet tellus feugiat, sit amet consequat lacus ultricies.</p>

<p>Donec imperdiet, lectus eget congue cursus, dolor enim finibus risus, ut molestie lorem tellus non tortor. Donec quam nibh, molestie in dapibus et, efficitur non tortor. Morbi orci tellus, mollis vel mi vitae, auctor lobortis erat. Ut gravida velit eget ligula lacinia, id rhoncus tellus gravida. Maecenas laoreet rutrum consequat. Suspendisse sed nibh dui. Curabitur dictum euismod mollis. Sed egestas libero libero, eu accumsan augue placerat non. Nunc id condimentum orci. Mauris vitae sollicitudin quam.</p>

<p><strong>Giphy Gifs will look like:</strong><br /></p>
<iframe src="https://giphy.com/embed/ZqlvCTNHpqrio" width="480" height="259" frameborder="0" class="giphy-embed" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
<p><a href="https://giphy.com/gifs/laughing-despicable-me-minions-ZqlvCTNHpqrio">via GIPHY</a></p>

<p><strong>YouTUbe Videos will look like:</strong><br /></p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/jTPXwbDtIpA" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="sample" /><category term="post" /><category term="test" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A sample post to show how the content will look and how will different headlines, quotes and codes will be represented.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How to Install and use WhatATheme?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/how-to-install-whatatheme" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Install and use WhatATheme?" /><published>2020-04-22T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-04-22T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/how-to-install-whatatheme</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/how-to-install-whatatheme"><![CDATA[<h1 id="what-is-whatatheme">What is WhatATheme?</h1>
<blockquote>
  <p>You’ll find this post in your <strong><em>_posts</em></strong> directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. &gt;You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">bundle exec jekyll serve</code>, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.</p>
</blockquote>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VfPa2c9kwhQ" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>

<hr />

<p><strong>WhatATheme</strong> is a customizable Jekyll Portfolio theme which supports blogging. You can use this theme in order to create an elegant, fully responsive portfolio which includes</p>

<h3 id="home-page--">Home Page -</h3>
<ul>
  <li>A Hero section - A section where you can outsource an image which will work as the background for the particular section; it also will include your name and a tagline which can be easily manipulated via the _config.yml file.</li>
  <li>An About section - A section where you can include your image and a 60 word paragraph which again you can easily manipulate using the _config.yml file.</li>
  <li>A Contact section - A section where you can include 3 direct ways to contact<br />
<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Ping on Messenger</code><br />
<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Send an Email</code><br />
<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Tweet on Twitter</code><br />
The contact section will also include 10 different social media buttons for your audience to follow.<br />
<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Facebook</code>, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Twitter</code>, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Instagram</code>, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">LinkedIn</code>, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">GitHub</code>, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">YouTube</code>, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Reddit</code>, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Behance</code>, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Dribbble</code> &amp; <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Spotify</code>.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="blog--">Blog -</h3>
<p>The blog includes a horizontal card list where the latest articles are fetched from the _posts folder automatically in top-down format. It also includes an instant search box which matches your query from the title, description &amp; content of your post and shows the result as soon as you type.<br />
The blog card includes</p>
<ul>
  <li>Post Title</li>
  <li>300 words from the content of the post</li>
  <li>The publish date</li>
  <li>The time which will be required to read the post.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="projects--">Projects -</h3>
<p>The Projects page will include all the projects from the <strong><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">projects.yml</code></strong> file which is present in the _data folder.<br />
Projects will be showcased in a card-list format where each card will contain</p>
<ul>
  <li>An image related to the project</li>
  <li>A Project Title</li>
  <li>A Project Description of about 80 words</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="footer--">Footer -</h3>
<p>The footer includes</p>
<ul>
  <li>A small about the author widget which show the same <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Author Image</code> as mentioned in the about section of the Home page which includes <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Name of the Author</code>, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Around 75 words about the author</code>.</li>
  <li>A more link widget which includes a link to any extra page that you’ve created and a <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Subscribe via RSS</code> link.</li>
  <li>A Recent posts widget which will include latest 3 posts.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="extra-features--">Extra Features -</h4>
<p>WhatATheme comes pre installed with</p>
<ul>
  <li><strong>HTML Compressor</strong> - It’ll compress all the pages by removing any extra space or blank lines.</li>
  <li><strong>Google Analytics</strong> - A web analytics service offered by Google that tracks and reports website traffic. For more information <a href="https://analytics.google.com" target="blank">click here</a>.</li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Disqus</strong> - A worldwide blog comment hosting service for web sites and online communities that use a networked platform. For more information about Disqus <a href="https://help.disqus.com/en/articles/1717053-what-is-disqus" target="blank">click here</a></p>

    <p>##### For more information about WhatATheme <a href="https://github.com/thedevslot/WhatATheme/blob/gh-pages/README.md" target="blank">click here</a>.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<hr />

<h1 id="installation">Installation</h1>
<h3 id="step-1---setting-up-whatatheme">Step 1 - Setting up WhatATheme</h3>
<blockquote>
  <ul>
    <li>Fork the <a href="https://github.com/thedevslot/WhatATheme/tree/master" target="blankl">repository</a></li>
    <li>Go to repository settings and set Github Pages source as master.</li>
    <li>Your new site should be ready at <a href="#" target="blank">https://username.github.io/WhatATheme/</a></li>
  </ul>
</blockquote>

<h3 id="step-2---making-changes-via-_configyml">Step 2 - Making changes via <strong>_config.yml</strong></h3>
<blockquote>
  <ul>
    <li>Open _config.yml file</li>
    <li>Fill the available details accordingly</li>
    <li>Commit the changes</li>
  </ul>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="how to" /><category term="setup" /><category term="theme" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This post will guide you to install WhatATheme on your Jekyll site, follow the easy steps to set up WhatATheme.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What is Jekyll? How to use it?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/what-is-jekyll-how-to-use-it" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What is Jekyll? How to use it?" /><published>2020-04-21T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-04-21T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/what-is-jekyll-how-to-use-it</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/what-is-jekyll-how-to-use-it"><![CDATA[<p>Jekyll is a simple, blog-aware, static site generator perfect for personal, project, or organization sites. Think of it like a file-based CMS, without all the complexity. Jekyll takes your content, renders Markdown and Liquid templates, and spits out a complete, static website ready to be served by Apache, Nginx or another web server. Jekyll is the engine behind GitHub Pages, which you can use to host sites right from your GitHub repositories and if you don’t know what GitHub Pages are you can visit on click <a href="https://help.github.com/en/github/working-with-github-pages/about-github-pages" target="blank">here</a> or <a href="https://pages.github.com/" target="blank">here</a></p>
<h6 id="source--jekyll-docs">Source : <a href="https://jekyllrb.com/docs/"><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Jekyll Docs</code></a></h6>

<blockquote>
  <h3 id="to-know-more-and-get-started-with-jekyll-you-can-click-here">To know more and get started with Jekyll you can click <a href="https://jekyllrb.com/" targe="_blank">here</a></h3>
</blockquote>

<h1 id="installation">Installation</h1>
<p><strong>Jekyll is a Ruby Gem that can be installed on most systems.</strong></p>
<h3 id="requirements">Requirements</h3>
<ul>
  <li><a href="https://www.ruby-lang.org/en/downloads/" target="_blank">Ruby</a> version 2.5.0 or above, including all development headers (ruby version can be checked by running ruby -v)</li>
  <li><a href="https://rubygems.org/pages/download" target="_blank">Ruby Gems</a> (which you can check by running gem -v)</li>
  <li><a href="https://gcc.gnu.org/install/" target="_blank">GCC</a> and <a href="https://www.gnu.org/software/make/" target="_blank">Make</a></li>
</ul>

<h3 id="after-installing-the-requirements-you-can-follow-these-guides">After Installing the Requirements you can follow these guides:</h3>
<p><strong>For detailed install instructions have a look at the guide for your operating system.</strong></p>
<ul>
  <li><a href="https://jekyllrb.com/docs/installation/macos/" target="_blank">macOS</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://jekyllrb.com/docs/installation/ubuntu/" target="_blank">Ubuntu</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://jekyllrb.com/docs/installation/other-linux/" target="_blank">Other Linux Distros</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://jekyllrb.com/docs/installation/windows/" target="_blank">Windows</a></li>
</ul>

<h3 id="creating-a-new-jekyll-site">Creating a new Jekyll site</h3>
<p><strong>We can create a new Jekyll site just by a simple command:</strong><br /></p>
<blockquote>
  <h1 id="jekyll-new-my-site"><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">jekyll new my-site</code></h1>
</blockquote>

<p>Jekyll will create a new directory named as <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">my-site</code> which is customizable (i.e., you can change the name from <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">my-site</code> to anything you want for example <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">jekyll new brutus</code>).</p>

<h3 id="changing-into-the-directory">Changing into the Directory</h3>
<p><strong>We have to go inside the directory:</strong><br /></p>
<blockquote>
  <h1 id="cd-my-site"><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">cd my-site</code></h1>
</blockquote>

<p>Again, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">my-site</code> is just a random name which is customizable.</p>

<h3 id="building-the-site-and-making-it-available-on-a-local-server">Building the site and making it available on a local server</h3>
<blockquote>
  <h1 id="bundle-exec-jekyll-serve"><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">bundle exec jekyll serve</code></h1>
</blockquote>

<h3 id="browsing-your-jekyll-site">Browsing your Jekyll site</h3>
<blockquote>
  <h1 id="browse-to-httplocalhost4000">Browse to <a href="http://localhost:4000/" target="_blank"><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">http://localhost:4000/</code></a></h1>
</blockquote>

<h6 id="on-encountering-any-problem-while-building-and-serving-your-jekyll-site-you-can-consider-visiting-to-the-troubleshooting-page">On encountering any problem while building and serving your Jekyll site you can consider visiting to the <a href="https://jekyllrb.com/docs/troubleshooting/#configuration-problems" target="_blank">troubleshooting</a> page</h6>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="informative" /><category term="technology" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jekyll is a static site generator. You give it text written in your favorite markup language and it uses layouts to create a static website.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to my blog!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/welcome" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to my blog!" /><published>2019-01-01T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-01-01T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/welcome</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/welcome"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome! I am Roman Surkoff, an experienced Java developer with a proven track record of delivering high-quality 
software solutions across various industries, including banking and government portals. I am passionate about 
collaborating with teams to streamline development processes and skilled in mentoring junior developers.</p>

<hr />

<p><b>
    Welcome to my blog!
</b>
<br /></p>

<p>Hello everyone, I’m Roman Surkoff, an experienced and results-oriented Java developer with a passion for delivering 
high-quality software solutions. With a strong track record of delivering successful projects across various industries, 
including banking software and government portals, I’m dedicated to continuous learning and growth 
in the field of software development.</p>

<p><br /></p>

<p>Throughout my career, I’ve been committed to collaborating with cross-functional teams to streamline the 
software development process and enhance code quality. As a skilled team leader, I’ve effectively managed and mentored 
junior developers, fostering a collaborative and productive work environment.</p>

<p><br /></p>

<p>Driven by the challenge of solving complex problems, I thrive in dynamic environments where I can apply my strong 
problem-solving skills and attention to detail. My focus is on delivering exceptional results, surpassing customer 
expectations, and contributing to the success of forward-thinking organizations.</p>

<p><br /></p>

<p>I’m excited to share my insights and experiences with you through this blog. Stay tuned for valuable content on 
software development, technology, and more. Thank you for joining me on this journey!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="hello-world" /><category term="post" /><category term="about" /><category term="welcome" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome! I am Roman Surkoff, an experienced Java developer with a proven track record of delivering high-quality software solutions in banking and government sectors while collaborating with teams and mentoring junior developers.]]></summary></entry></feed>